<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resources>
    <string name="bp_info_content_what_is_bp">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;What is blood pressure?&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Blood pressure is the pressure that blood exerts on the walls of blood vessels during circulation to organs in the body. Arterial resistance and the force of contraction of the heart are the two main factors that make up blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Blood pressure readings in a normal person will be higher during the day and lower at night. The time from 1 to 3 am when the body is fast asleep is when the blood pressure is at its lowest, and from 8 to 10 am is the time when the blood pressure is at its highest.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Blood pressure will often increase when we exercise, nervous tension, vasoconstriction (due to cold or taking vasopressors), eating too salty or experiencing a strong emotional state. Conversely, when you relax, rest, take vasodilators, sweat a lot, in a hot environment, have diarrhea, etc., your blood pressure will drop.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Blood pressure is expressed through the following two numbers:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Systolic blood pressure (maximum blood pressure): a normal level of 90 - 139 mm Hg;&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Diastolic blood pressure (minimum blood pressure): a normal level is between 60 - 89 mm Hg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;If the blood pressure reading is higher than the above standards, it is considered high blood pressure, otherwise it is low blood pressure. When the heart beats, blood pressure goes from maximum to minimum (changes from systolic pressure to diastolic pressure). As blood moves farther from the heart to the arteries, blood pressure will decrease.&lt;/p&gt;]]</string>
    <string name="bp_info_content_at_a_normal_bp_range">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;Am I in the Normal BP range?&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;People with normal blood pressure readings are measured at:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Systolic blood pressure: 90 - 130 mmHg;&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Diastolic blood pressure: 60-90 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;A person who is determined to have low blood pressure will have the following measurements:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Systolic blood pressure: &amp;lt; 85 mmHg and/or:&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Diastolic blood pressure: &amp;lt;60 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;For cases of hypertension will be divided into the following grades:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Prehypertension: systolic blood pressure 130 - 139 mmHg and/or diastolic blood pressure 85 - 89 mmHg;&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Grade 1 hypertension: systolic blood pressure 140 - 159 mmHg and/or diastolic blood pressure 90 - 99 mmHg;&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Grade 2 hypertension: systolic blood pressure 160 - 179 mmHg and/or diastolic blood pressure 100 - 109 mmHg;&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Grade 3 hypertension: systolic blood pressure &amp;ge; 180 mmHg and/or diastolic blood pressure &amp;ge; 110 mmHg;&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Isolated systolic hypertension: Systolic blood pressure &amp;ge; 140 mmHg and diastolic blood pressure &amp;lt; 90 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;However, the above safe blood pressure index will be relative and also need to be based on each age level.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Detailed blood pressure chart by ages&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Depending on age, blood pressure levels can also vary slightly. You should know this index table to have more adjustments in eating and living, when the blood pressure index is unstable.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 1 to 12 months: The standard blood pressure is stable at 75/50 mmHg and the maximum blood pressure at this age is 100/70 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 1 to 4 years: The standard blood pressure is stable at 80/50 mmHg and the maximum blood pressure at this age is 110/70 mm/Hg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 3 to 5 years old: The standard blood pressure is stable at 80/50 mmHg and the maximum blood pressure at this age is 110/70 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 6-13 years old: A stable blood pressure standard will be 85/55 mmHg and the maximum level of blood pressure at this age is 120/80 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 13-15 years old: A stable blood pressure level is 95/60 mmHg, and a maximum blood pressure at this age is 140/90 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 15-19 years old: At this age, the normal blood pressure index is defined as: Minimum-BP reading is 105/73 mmHg, mean BP reading is :117/77 mmHg, maximum BP reading is :117/77 mmHg. with readings: 120/81 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 20-24 years old: At this age, the normal blood pressure index is defined as: Minimum-BP reading is 108/75 mmHg, mean BP reading is :120/79 mmHg, maximum BP reading is :120/79 mmHg. with readings: 132/83 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 25-29 years old: At this age, the normal blood pressure index is defined as: Minimum-BP reading is 109/76 mmHg, mean BP reading is :121/80 mmHg, maximum BP reading is :121/80 mmHg index is: 133/84 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 30-34 years old: At this age, the normal blood pressure index is defined as: Minimum-BP reading is 110/77 mmHg, mean BP reading is :122/81 mmHg, maximum BP reading is :122/81 mmHg index is: 134/85 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 35-39 years old: At this age, the normal blood pressure index is defined as: Minimum-BP reading is 111/78 mmHg, mean BP reading is :123/82 mmHg, maximum BP reading is :123/82 mmHg index is: 135/86 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 40-44 years old: At this age, the normal blood pressure index is defined as: Minimum-BP readings 112/79 mmHg, mean BP readings :125/83 mmHg, maximum BP readings: 125/83 mmHg index is: 137/87 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 45-49 years old: At this age, the normal blood pressure index is defined as: Minimum-BP readings 115/80 mmHg, mean BP readings :127/84 mmHg, maximum BP readings: 127/84 mmHg. index is: 139/88 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 50-54 years old: At this age, the normal blood pressure index is defined as: Minimum-BP reading is 116/81 mmHg, mean BP reading is :129/85 mmHg, maximum BP reading is :129/85 mmHg. with readings: 142/89 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 55-59 years old: At this age, the normal blood pressure index is defined as: Minimum-BP readings 118/82 mmHg, mean BP readings :131/86 mmHg, maximum BP readings: 131/86 mmHg. index is: 144/90 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;From 60-64 years old: At this age, the normal blood pressure index is defined as: Minimum-BP readings 121/83 mmHg, mean BP readings :134/87 mmHg, maximum BP readings: 134/87 mmHg. has an index of: 147/91 mmHg.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;]]</string>
    <string name="bp_info_content_how_to_measure_bp">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;How to measure blood pressure?&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Electronic blood pressure monitors are the most commonly used devices in every household. These devices are easy to use and have clear display indicators. To accurately measure blood pressure, users should follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Timing of blood pressure measurement:&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Usually, blood pressure is measured in the morning for daily monitoring. However, blood pressure may slightly increase after physical activities or when measured in the evening. Users can also choose a specific time during the day to measure their blood pressure or measure it multiple times a day to compare the readings.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Seated posture during blood pressure measurement:&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;It is advisable to sit with a straight back and keep the arm comfortable when measuring blood pressure. It is best to relax for about 10-15 minutes before measuring. Also, avoid measuring blood pressure immediately after exercise, physical exertion, climbing stairs, or right after a meal when feeling too full or too hungry, as the readings at these times may not be accurate.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Position for blood pressure measurement:&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Electronic blood pressure measurement is very simple. You can choose to measure it at the wrist or upper arm:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Measurement at the upper arm: Place the arm palm-up on a table, parallel to the body. The sensing point should be located on the elbow crease, about 2cm above it, and proceed with the measurement.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Measurement at the wrist: Fold the arm at a 45-degree angle so that the wrist is level with the heart, and proceed with the measurement.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Important steps to remember when measuring blood pressure:&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Once the correct position is chosen, the user should sit still, maintain the position, and press the start button on the device to begin the blood pressure measurement process. This position should be maintained until the machine indicates and displays the result, and then turn off the device.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Do not eat, drink, or talk during the blood pressure measurement. It is recommended to measure blood pressure twice a day, in the morning before taking medication and in the evening. It is advisable to keep a record of blood pressure readings to assess health for future health check-ups.&lt;/p&gt;]]</string>
    <string name="bp_info_content_type_of_bp">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;Types of blood pressure&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The arterial system is subjected to pressure exerted by the blood, which helps pump blood to nourish organs throughout the body. This pressure is known as blood pressure and is determined based on the blood flow into the heart. In cases where the heart receives too much blood, it can cause narrowing of the arteries, leading to high blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Blood pressure is divided into two types:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Systolic blood pressure: This is the maximum blood pressure, a form of pressure that occurs when blood is pumped out of the heart and into the arteries.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Diastolic blood pressure: This is the minimum blood pressure, measured when the heart is at rest between beats. The value of this index will be lower than the systolic blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;]]</string>
    <string name="bp_info_content_hypertension">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;What is Hypertension?&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;High blood pressure is a common condition, especially in older individuals. As follows:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;What is high blood pressure?&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;High blood pressure refers to a condition where the blood pressure on the arterial walls is higher than normal. In a normal state, the two blood pressure measurements, systolic and diastolic, are 120/80 mmHg. When the systolic blood pressure is &amp;gt;140 mmHg and/or the diastolic blood pressure is &amp;gt;90 mmHg, the patient is diagnosed with high blood pressure. The severity of high blood pressure can vary based on the changes in these measurements.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;If high blood pressure is not well controlled, it can lead to serious health issues, especially the risk of coronary artery disease, stroke, and potentially fatal outcomes or significant long-term health consequences, reducing the patient&amp;apos;s quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Symptoms of high blood pressure:&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The symptoms of high blood pressure can vary depending on its severity. In the early stages, the disease may not present noticeable symptoms. However, individuals with consistently high blood pressure may experience common signs of abnormal blood pressure elevation such as blurred vision, dizziness, headaches, nausea, unsteadiness, and fainting. In severe cases of high blood pressure, it can lead to ruptured blood vessels, stroke, coronary artery disease, and death.&lt;/p&gt;]]</string>
    <string name="bp_info_content_lifestyle_for_hypertension">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;Lifestyle for hypertension&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Regular exercise&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;If you do not have hypertension, regular exercise can help prevent this condition. If you already have hypertension, regular physical activity can help lower your blood pressure to a safer level. Numerous studies have shown that engaging in at least 150 minutes of exercise per week can reduce blood pressure by 5-8mmHg in individuals with hypertension. It is important to maintain a consistent exercise routine because if you stop exercising, your blood pressure is likely to increase again.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Some suitable exercises for people with hypertension include walking, jogging, cycling, swimming, dancing, and high-intensity interval training. You can also engage in high-intensity exercise for 10 minutes, followed by gentle exercise, and repeat this cycle every 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Healthy eating habits&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;According to the Dietary Approaches to Stop Hypertension (DASH) diet, adhering to a menu that includes whole grains, good sources of protein, foods rich in calcium, potassium, magnesium, fruits, and vegetables can reduce blood pressure by up to 11mmHg. It is also important to eliminate saturated fats and cholesterol from your diet, as studies have shown that a low-carbohydrate and refined sugar diet effectively stabilizes blood pressure. Specifically, individuals who followed a low-carbohydrate and low-sugar diet for six weeks experienced improvements in blood pressure and other cardiovascular indicators compared to those who did not follow this diet.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Salt is also considered the &amp;quot;bane&amp;quot; of individuals with hypertension. Even reducing a small amount of sodium in your diet can improve cardiovascular health and lower blood pressure by approximately 5-6mmHg in people with hypertension.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Limit alcohol intake&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Moderate alcohol consumption (1 glass per day for women or 2 glasses per day for men) can reduce blood pressure by approximately 4mmHg. However, this effect is lost if you consume excessive amounts of alcohol. Drinking more than the recommended limit can increase blood pressure and reduce the effectiveness of hypertension medications.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Quit smoking&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Each cigarette you smoke causes a sudden increase in blood pressure, even after you finish smoking. Therefore, quitting smoking today can help normalize your blood pressure. Quitting smoking also reduces the risk of cardiovascular disease and improves overall health. Studies have shown that non-smokers have a longer life expectancy compared to long-term smokers.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Reduce caffeine intake&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The role of caffeine in blood pressure is still debated. Caffeine can increase blood pressure by up to 10mmHg in individuals who are not accustomed to consuming caffeine regularly. However, individuals who regularly drink coffee believe that caffeine has little or no effect on their blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;To determine if caffeine raises your blood pressure, measure your blood pressure within 30 minutes after consuming a caffeinated beverage. If your blood pressure increases by 5-10mmHg, it indicates that your body is sensitive to caffeine. In that case, you should reduce your daily caffeine intake.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Reduce Stress&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Chronic stress can contribute to high blood pressure. Take some time to reflect on the causes of your stress, such as work, family, finances, or illness. Once you identify what causes stress for you, you need to find ways to address and eliminate it from your life.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;apos;re facing issues at work, talk to your supervisor, reduce your workload, and prioritize rest and relaxation. If you&amp;apos;re experiencing conflicts with your children or spouse, have direct conversations with them to gradually resolve the misunderstandings.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Try to avoid stressors. For example, if you frequently experience stress due to traffic congestion when commuting to work, wake up earlier, avoid peak traffic hours, or use public transportation. If there&amp;apos;s a colleague in your company who always makes you uncomfortable and stressed during conversations, try to minimize interactions with that person.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Allocate time for relaxation and engage in activities you enjoy, such as going for a walk, cooking, or participating in volunteer work. Traveling can also be an effective way to relieve stress if you have the time.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Meditation or deep breathing exercises: Both meditation and deep breathing activate the parasympathetic nervous system. This system functions when the body is relaxed, slowing down the heart rate and reducing blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Ensure sufficient and quality sleep&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Blood pressure tends to decrease while we sleep. Inadequate and shallow sleep can have a significant impact on blood pressure. That&amp;apos;s why people who frequently experience insomnia or lack of sleep, especially older adults, are at risk of developing high blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;To improve the quality of sleep, try implementing the following practices:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;- Establish a consistent bedtime routine: Ideally, before 11 PM.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;- Allocate relaxation time before going to bed: Listen to music, read books, play with your child, or watch a gentle romantic movie instead of using electronic devices like laptops or smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;- Engage in regular exercise.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;- Avoid napping for more than 30 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;- Design a comfortable and pleasant bedroom space: Pay attention to appropriate temperature and lighting, and consider using herbal essential oils for relaxation, making it easier to fall asleep and sleep better.&lt;/p&gt;]]</string>
    <string name="bp_info_content_why_is_it_a_risk_factory">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;Hypertension: Why is it a risk factor?&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;From the aforementioned causes of high blood pressure, it can be seen that it is difficult to determine the mechanisms of action and the underlying causes of the disease for early proactive prevention. This condition is considered a &amp;quot;silent killer.&amp;quot; The disease can cause the following complications:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Coronary heart disease&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;High blood pressure is a problem caused by the pressure of the blood vessels. When this condition occurs, the coronary arteries become blocked, significantly reducing blood flow to the heart. Patients often experience symptoms such as left-sided chest pain, prolonged pain lasting 15-20 minutes, which may radiate to the arm.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Increased risk of stroke&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;High blood pressure can lead to left ventricular hypertrophy, especially in obese or elderly individuals. This condition increases the risk of heart failure, stroke, and mortality. Elderly patients with high blood pressure need to be particularly careful as excessive stress, psychological shock, or excessive fatigue can easily lead to stroke.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Other dangerous complications&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Due to the difficult identification of the causes of high blood pressure, treatment for many patients is often challenging. This leads to an increased risk of other dangerous complications. These include severe conditions such as cerebral vascular accidents (strokes), arteriosclerosis, impaired vision, and impaired motor function. Patients with high blood pressure need regular health monitoring and daily blood pressure monitoring to control the risk of abnormal blood pressure increases.&lt;/p&gt;]]</string>
    <string name="bp_info_content_how_does_hypertension_affect_brain">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;How does hypertension affect the brain?&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;If left untreated, high blood pressure can cause the heart to work harder, leading to fatigue and exerting pressure on the large blood vessels, increasing the risk of cardiovascular diseases such as heart attack, stroke, coronary artery disease, heart failure, kidney failure, and vision loss.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Specifically, high blood pressure affects the brain of patients. It increases the risk of cerebral hemorrhage in patients with high blood pressure by 10 times compared to those without high blood pressure. Even slightly elevated blood pressure increases the risk of stroke.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;In fact, up to 80% of cases of chest pain and stroke are caused by high blood pressure. High blood pressure weakens and ruptures the small blood vessels in the brain. If blood flow to the brain is interrupted, it can lead to insufficient blood supply to the brain.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The body may experience symptoms such as seeing spots or dizziness. If the condition is severe and prolonged, it can increase the risk of mild cognitive impairment, memory loss, and ruptured blood vessels in the brain, leading to paralysis and cerebral hemorrhage. The most serious risk for patients with high blood pressure is death if they are not promptly treated in an emergency.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;In addition, several studies have also shown that young people with blood pressure above the normal threshold are at risk of brain shrinkage. For individuals with high blood pressure, there are changes in the gray matter of the brain. Gray matter plays an important role in the brain as it contains most of the nerve cells and is essential for neurological function. When the gray matter is affected, it increases the risk of stroke and early memory loss compared to individuals with normal blood pressure.&lt;/p&gt;]]</string>
    <string name="bp_info_content_how_bp_affect_the_kidneys">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;How does blood pressure affect the kidneys?&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;High blood pressure can cause the thickening of blood vessel walls, narrowing the blood vessels. As a result, waste products in the body may accumulate in the blood. If left untreated for a long time, it can have an impact on the kidneys, leading to the most severe complication, which is kidney failure (also known as renal failure).&lt;/p&gt;]]</string>
    <string name="bp_info_content_how_does_bp_affect_other_organs">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;How does blood pressure affect other organs?&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Effects on the eyes: High blood pressure can cause eye disorders such as retinopathy and blindness. When blood pressure is elevated, it affects all blood vessels in the body, including those that nourish the eyes. Insufficient blood supply to the eyes can lead to dryness, gradual blurring, weakened vision, and restricted vision, resulting in retinopathy and, if left untreated, eventually leading to blindness.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Peripheral arterial disease: Untreated high blood pressure can affect the blood vessels in the extremities. It narrows and hardens the blood vessels in the arms and legs, leading to symptoms such as cramping or peripheral arterial disease, causing pain for the affected individuals.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Bone loss: Increased blood pressure can disrupt calcium metabolism, leading to increased calcium excretion from the body, especially in older women. Prolonged bone loss can result in osteoporosis and fractures due to weakened bones.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Effects on pregnancy: Pregnant women with high blood pressure can reduce blood flow to the placenta, resulting in reduced oxygen and nutrient supply to the fetus. This can lead to fetal growth restriction and abnormal development. The most dangerous complication for pregnant women with high blood pressure is preeclampsia, which can cause serious complications for both the mother and the fetus. Research has shown that high blood pressure during pregnancy can increase the risk of stroke in women by up to 40%.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Complications in arteries: Blockage or narrowing of the carotid arteries, peripheral arteries, or arteries at the back of the eye can lead to permanent vision loss.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Other complications: Decreased sexual and reproductive function.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;]]</string>
    <string name="bp_info_content_dianosing_hypertension">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;Diagnosing hypertension&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The World Health Organization (WHO) defines the diagnosis of high blood pressure as having an average systolic blood pressure of &amp;ge;140 mmHg and/or an average diastolic blood pressure of &amp;ge;90 mmHg, measured on at least two separate occasions during consecutive medical visits. Currently, the use of home blood pressure monitoring devices is widely popular and convenient for patients to monitor their condition. To confirm the diagnosis using home blood pressure measurement, the following three factors should be ensured:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;1. Each blood pressure measurement should be taken twice consecutively, with a 1-minute interval, while in a seated position.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;2. Blood pressure should be measured twice a day, preferably once in the morning and once in the evening.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;3. Continuous blood pressure measurement should be conducted for at least 4 days, ideally for 7 days. The first day&amp;apos;s readings should be discarded, and the average values of the remaining measurements (&amp;ge;135/85 mmHg) should be used to confirm the diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;While awaiting confirmation of high blood pressure, further investigations should be conducted to detect target organ damage (such as left ventricular hypertrophy, chronic kidney disease, and hypertensive retinopathy) and assess cardiovascular risk.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Individuals with normal blood pressure should have their blood pressure rechecked every 2 years, and individuals with pre-hypertension should make lifestyle changes and have their blood pressure rechecked after 1 year.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Causes of high blood pressure:&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Approximately 90-95% of cases of high blood pressure are classified as primary hypertension, which is defined as elevated blood pressure without identifiable secondary causes. The remaining cases are classified as secondary hypertension, caused by specific underlying conditions (e.g., heart, kidney issues). Hypertension related to kidney disease, although accounting for only 2-3% of hypertensive individuals, is one of the most common secondary causes of hypertension. The majority of hypertension related to kidney disease is directly associated with reduced renal blood flow as a consequence of renal artery stenosis or stenosis in one of its branches. Other causes include adrenal cortical abnormalities, changes in aldosterone secretion, Cushing&amp;apos;s syndrome, Conn&amp;apos;s syndrome, etc. Additionally, there can be alterations in the extracellular fluid volume regulation due to inappropriate activation of the renin-angiotensin-aldosterone system, resulting in sodium and water retention, chronic high blood pressure, and subsequent hypertension.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Symptoms of high blood pressure:&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;High blood pressure often has few symptoms, but it may present as headaches, palpitations, fatigue, chest pain, or difficulty breathing. Many cases of high blood pressure go unnoticed as there are no noticeable abnormal signs.&lt;/p&gt;]]</string>
</resources>