<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resources>
    <string name="info_bs_normal_blood_sugar_level"><![CDATA[<h1>Normal Blood Sugar Level</h1>\n<p>Blood sugar (or blood glucose) is the body\'s main source of energy and is also an extremely important and necessary fuel source for organs, especially the nervous system and brain.</p>\n<p>The glycemic index (GI) is defined as a value indicating the concentration of glucose in the blood, usually measured in units of mmol/l or mg/dl. Blood glucose levels continuously change day by day, even minute by minute, especially related to daily diet and activities. There is always a certain amount of sugar in the blood. If the blood sugar level is constantly high, it will lead to diabetes and complications affecting many organs, especially the kidneys, blood vessels, etc.</p>\n<p>Blood sugar index is divided into 4 types: random blood sugar, fasting blood sugar, 1 hour post-meal blood sugar and 2 hour post-meal blood sugar and blood sugar is expressed through HbA1C index.</p>\n<p>The blood sugar index helps determine the level of glucose in a person\'s blood at the time of the survey. From there, we can determine whether the patient is normal, pre-diabetic or diabetic.</p>\n<p>The safe blood sugar index for normal people is as follows:</p>\n<ul>\n<li>Random blood sugar: &lt; 140 mg/dL (7.8 mmol/l).</li>\n<li>Fasting blood sugar: &lt; 100 mg/dL (&lt; 5.6 mmol/l).</li>\n<li>After meals: &lt; 140mg/dl (7.8 mmol/l).</li>\n<li>HbA1C: &lt; 5.7 %.</li>\n</ul>\n<p>Details:</p>\n<ul>\n<li>Fasting blood sugar:</li>\n</ul>\n<p>The fasting blood sugar index is measured for the first time in the morning, fasting for at least 8 hours or so when you have not eaten or drank any food. The fasting blood sugar index is around 70 mg/dL (3.9 mmol). /L) and 92 mg/dL (5.0 mmol/L) is normal.</p>\n<p>Through research, medical experts have found that people with fasting blood sugar levels in this range have no risk of developing diabetes within the next 10 years or longer.</p>\n<ul>\n<li>Blood sugar after meals:</li>\n</ul>\n<p>The postprandial blood sugar index of a normal healthy person is less than 140mg/dL (7.8 mmol/L) measured within 1 - 2 hours after eating.</p>\n<ul>\n<li>Blood sugar at bedtime:</li>\n</ul>\n<p>Normal people\'s blood sugar before going to bed will range from 110-150mg/dl (equivalent to 6.0-8.3mmol/l).</p>\n<ul>\n<li>Hemoglobin A1c (HbA1c) test:</li>\n</ul>\n<p>HbA1c below 48 mmol/mol (6.5%) is normal. HbA1C is often used to diagnose diabetes.</p>\n<p>Blood sugar levels below 70 mg/dL (3.9 mmol/L) are considered hypoglycemic. This is a dangerous condition and requires immediate emergency treatment. This drop in blood sugar can continue and cause the patient to fall into a coma and cause brain damage.</p>\n<p>However, if blood sugar levels are high, it may be because the ability of pancreatic cells to secrete insulin is reduced or there is enough insulin in the body but is ineffective (insulin resistance). To meet the body\'s needs, the pancreas must work harder and harder until it is overloaded and damaged. Besides, it also causes blood vessels to harden, also known as atherosclerosis. Most parts of the body are susceptible to damage due to high blood sugar levels.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="info_bs_diabetes"><![CDATA[<h1>Diabetes</h1>\n<p>Diabetes is a chronic disease that occurs either when the pancreas does not produce enough insulin or when the body cannot effectively use the insulin it produces. Insulin is a hormone that regulates blood glucose. Hyperglycaemia, also called raised blood glucose or raised blood sugar, is a common effect of uncontrolled diabetes and over time leads to serious damage to many of the body\'s systems, especially the nerves and blood vessels.</p>\n<p>Over time, that can cause serious health problems, such as heart disease, vision loss, and kidney disease.</p>\n<p>There isn&rsquo;t a cure yet for diabetes, but losing weight, eating healthy food, and being active can really help. Other things you can do to help:</p>\n<ul>\n<li>Take medicine as prescribed.</li>\n<li>Get diabetes self-management education and support.</li>\n<li>Make and keep health care appointments.</li>\n</ul>]]></string>
    <string name="info_bs_how_common_is_diabetes"><![CDATA[<h1>How common is Diabetes?</h1>\n<p>In 2014, 8.5% of adults aged 18 years and older had diabetes. In 2019, diabetes was the direct cause of 1.5 million deaths and 48% of all deaths due to diabetes occurred before the age of 70 years. Another 460 000 kidney disease deaths were caused by diabetes, and raised blood glucose causes around 20% of cardiovascular deaths <em>(1)</em>.</p>\n<p>Between 2000 and 2019, there was a 3% increase in age-standardized mortality rates from diabetes. In lower-middle-income countries, the mortality rate due to diabetes increased 13%.</p>\n<p>By contrast, the probability of dying from any one of the four main noncommunicable diseases (cardiovascular diseases, cancer, chronic respiratory diseases or diabetes) between the ages of 30 and 70 decreased by 22% globally between 2000 and 2019.&nbsp;</p>]]></string>
    <string name="info_bs_diabetes_symptoms"><![CDATA[<h1>Diabetes Symptoms</h1>\n<p>Symptoms of diabetes may occur suddenly. In type 2 diabetes, the symptoms can be mild and may take many years to be noticed.</p>\n<p>Symptoms of diabetes include:</p>\n<ul>\n<li>feeling very thirsty</li>\n<li>needing to urinate more often than usual</li>\n<li>blurred vision</li>\n<li>feeling tired</li>\n<li>losing weight unintentionally</li>\n</ul>\n<p>Over time, diabetes can damage blood vessels in the heart, eyes, kidneys and nerves.</p>\n<p>People with diabetes have a higher risk of health problems including heart attack, stroke and kidney failure.</p>\n<p>Diabetes can cause permanent vision loss by damaging blood vessels in the eyes.</p>\n<p>Many people with diabetes develop problems with their feet from nerve damage and poor blood flow. This can cause foot ulcers and may lead to amputation.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="info_bs_diabetes_types"><![CDATA[<h1>Diabetes Types</h1>\n<h2><strong>Type 1 diabetes</strong></h2>\n<p>Type 1 diabetes (previously known as insulin-dependent, juvenile or childhood-onset) is characterized by deficient insulin production and requires daily administration of insulin. In 2017 there were 9 million people with type 1 diabetes; the majority of them live in high-income countries. Neither its cause nor the means to prevent it are known.</p>\n<h2><strong>Type 2 diabetes</strong></h2>\n<p>Type 2 diabetes affects how your body uses sugar (glucose) for energy. It stops the body from using insulin properly, which can lead to high levels of blood sugar if not treated.</p>\n<p>Over time, type 2 diabetes can cause serious damage to the body, especially nerves and blood vessels.</p>\n<p>Type 2 diabetes is often preventable. Factors that contribute to developing type 2 diabetes include being overweight, not getting enough exercise, and genetics.</p>\n<p>Early diagnosis is important to prevent the worst effects of type 2 diabetes. The best way to detect diabetes early is to get regular check-ups and blood tests with a healthcare provider.</p>\n<p>Symptoms of type 2 diabetes can be mild. They may take several years to be noticed. Symptoms may be similar to those of type 1 diabetes but are often less marked. As a result, the disease may be diagnosed several years after onset, after complications have already arisen.</p>\n<p>More than 95% of people with diabetes have type 2 diabetes. Type 2 diabetes was formerly called non-insulin dependent, or adult onset. Until recently, this type of diabetes was seen only in adults but it is now also occurring increasingly frequently in children.</p>\n<h2><strong>Gestational diabetes</strong></h2>\n<p>Gestational diabetes is hyperglycaemia with blood glucose values above normal but below those diagnostic of diabetes. Gestational diabetes occurs during pregnancy.</p>\n<p>Women with gestational diabetes are at an increased risk of complications during pregnancy and at delivery. These women and possibly their children are also at increased risk of type 2 diabetes in the future.</p>\n<p>Gestational diabetes is diagnosed through prenatal screening, rather than through reported symptoms.</p>]]></string>
</resources>