<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resources><string name="info_hr_heart_rate">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;Heart Rate&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Your heart rate is the number of times that your heart beats in a minute. Your body automatically controls your heartbeat to match whatever you&amp;apos;re doing or what&amp;apos;s happening around you. That&amp;apos;s why your heartbeat gets faster when you&amp;apos;re active, excited or scared, and drops when you&amp;apos;re resting, calm or comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Your heart rate is an important indicator of your overall health too. When your heart rate is too fast or too slow, that can be a sign of heart or other health problems. The ability to feel your heart rate throughout your body is also a potential way for doctors to diagnose medical conditions.&lt;/p&gt;</string><string name="info_hr_resting_heart_rate">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;Resting Heart Rate&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;A resting heart rate refers to the point at which the heart pumps the lowest amount of blood the body needs when not exercising, staying calm, relaxing, sitting, or lying down, and without any underlying medical conditions. The normal heart rate for adults ranges from 60 to 100 beats per minute and can vary by the minute. Age and overall health also influence the heart rate, so the normal heart rate will differ for each person.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;It&amp;apos;s important to determine whether an individual&amp;apos;s normal heart rate falls within the normal range. If one is ill or experiences an injury that weakens the heart, the organs won&amp;apos;t receive enough blood to function normally. The healthier a person is, the lower their normal heart rate tends to be. For instance, athletes might have a resting heart rate of 40 to 60 beats per minute or even lower.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;An unusually high or low heart rate can indicate underlying health issues. Patients should consult a doctor if their normal resting heart rate is consistently above 100 beats per minute (fast heart rate) or below 60 beats per minute (slow heart rate) when not associated with being an athlete.&lt;/p&gt;</string><string name="info_hr_measure_resting_heart_rate">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;Measure Resting Heart Rate&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;It&amp;apos;s easy to check your pulse using just your fingers, either at the wrist or the side of the neck.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;At the wrist, lightly press the index and middle fingers of one hand on the opposite wrist, just below the base of the thumb.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;At the neck, lightly press the side of the neck, just below your jawbone.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Count the number of beats in 15 seconds, and multiply by four. That&amp;apos;s your heart rate.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;To get the most accurate reading, you may want to repeat a few times and use the average of the three values. For a resting heart rate measurement, you should also follow these steps:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Do not measure your heart rate within one to two hours after exercise or a stressful event. Your heart rate can stay elevated after strenuous activities.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Wait an hour after consuming caffeine, which can cause heart palpitations and make your heart rate rise.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;Do not take the reading after you have been sitting or standing for a long period, which can affect your heart rate.&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;You can also use different types of heart rate monitors to check your heart rate. But be aware that most have not undergone independent testing for accuracy. One option is a digital fitness tracker. The most reliable ones use a wireless sensor on a strap that you wrap around your chest. The sensor detects your pulse electronically and sends the data to a wristwatch-style receiver that displays your heart rate. Others have sensors on the back of the wristwatch itself. These sensors, which are slightly less accurate, determine your heart rate by measuring blood flow through the skin.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Various smartphone apps to check your heart rate are also available. For most of these, you place your finger on the phone&amp;apos;s camera lens, which then detects color changes in your finger each time your heart beats.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Treadmills, elliptical machines, and other exercise equipment found in fitness centers and some home exercise rooms often feature handgrip heart rate monitors. These rely on trace amounts of sweat from your palms and the metal on the grips to detect the electric signal of your heartbeat. But experts don&amp;apos;t recommend these to check your heart rate, as they are notoriously inaccurate.&lt;/p&gt;</string><string name="info_hr_when_to_check_resting_heart_rate">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;When To Check Your Resting Heart Rate?&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The most suitable time to measure your resting heart rate is in the early morning right after waking up, before getting out of bed, and even better if you had a good night&amp;apos;s sleep. Use the method mentioned to measure your resting heart rate, and then record the results. You might also need to check your heart rate for several consecutive days to ensure the accuracy of the readings.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;According to the American Heart Association (AHA), the average resting heart rate is around 60-80 beats per minute. However, this number gradually increases with age, and for individuals engaged in high-intensity athletic training, the resting heart rate will be lower.&lt;/p&gt;</string><string name="info_hr_target_heart_rate">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;Target Heart Rate&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;For moderate-intensity physical activity, your target heart rate should be between 64% and 76%1,2 of your maximum heart rate. You can estimate your maximum heart rate based on your age. To estimate your maximum age-related heart rate, subtract your age from 220. For example, for a 50-year-old person, the estimated maximum age-related heart rate would be calculated as 220 &amp;ndash; 50 years = 170 beats per minute (bpm). The 64% and 76% levels would be:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;64% level: 170 x 0.64 = 109 bpm, and&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;76% level: 170 x 0.76 = 129 bpm&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;This shows that moderate-intensity physical activity for a 50-year-old person will require that the heart rate remains between 109 and 129 bpm during physical activity.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;For vigorous-intensity physical activity, your target heart rate should be between 77% and 93%1,2 of your maximum heart rate. To figure out this range, follow the same formula used above, except change &amp;ldquo;64 and 76%&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;77 and 93%&amp;rdquo;. For example, for a 35-year-old person, the estimated maximum age-related heart rate would be calculated as 220 &amp;ndash; 35 years = 185 beats per minute (bpm). The 77% and 93% levels would be:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;77% level: 185 x 0.77 = 142 bpm, and&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n    &lt;li&gt;\n        &lt;p&gt;93% level: 185 x 0.93 = 172 bpm&lt;/p&gt;\n    &lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;This shows that vigorous-intensity physical activity for a 35-year-old person will require that the heart rate remains between 142 and 172 bpm during physical activity.&lt;/p&gt;</string><string name="info_hr_tachycardia">&lt;![CDATA[&lt;h1&gt;Tachycardia&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;When you have tachycardia, your heart beats faster than normal for a few seconds to a few hours. Normally, your heart rate is 60 to 100 beats per minute when you&amp;rsquo;re not active. When your heart beats more than 100 times a minute at rest, that&amp;rsquo;s tachycardia.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Because your heart beats too often, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have the time it needs to fill with blood between beats. This can be dangerous if your heart can&amp;rsquo;t supply all of your cells with the blood and oxygen they need.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Your heart normally responds to electrical signals from your heart&amp;rsquo;s sinoatrial (SA) node. These signals control how often your heart beats. When you&amp;rsquo;ve had a scare or are very emotional or anxious, or are exercising, your heart may send signals more frequently for a short time. This is called sinus tachycardia and goes away when you calm down or rest.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Other types of tachycardia can come back regularly and can be more serious.&lt;/p&gt;</string></resources>