<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resources>

<string name="water_info_avoid_drink_mistake">&lt;h1&gt;Avoid These Water Drinking Mistakes&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;If vitamins, minerals, protein, fats, water, and carbohydrates are essential for survival, so is water. It not just keeps us hydrated, but ensures that our body functions properly. No wonder that health experts advise us to drink at least eight to ten glasses of water every single day. &lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;When it comes to drinking water, the ample quantity is not enough to take care of. You should also know the right way to drink water for better health. Most of us make common mistakes such as drinking water while standing, and these kinds of mistakes can put us in trouble. &lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Here are five mistakes that you can make while drinking water, but you should avoid:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;1. Do not drink water while standing&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Aren’t we all just used to sipping on water while standing? Although you might have never thought about whether this is the right way to drink water or not, you may have been reminded by your elders at least once that water must be consumed when you are in a sitting position. &lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;One’s nerves get tensed while drinking water when standing. It can disturb the fluid balance, and cause indigestion. By standing and drinking, water goes to the lower part of the stomach, and we will not get nutrients.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;2. Avoiding gulping water quickly&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Whenever we are in a hurry, we try to drink water in one breath as much as we can. But it’s harmful. If you are in a hurry, just do not gulp the water as the impurities in the kidney and the bladder can accumulate below. Just have small sips of water to aid digestion. Therefore, it is advisable to have water slowly as it has various benefits.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;3. Avoid drinking water just before the meal&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Your stomach should be filled with 50 percent food, 25 percent water, and 25 percent should be left empty for the digestive process. That’s why drinking water just before eating a meal is not a great idea. Doing so can make you feel fuller, and then you will not be able to eat enough food. You will not be able to get the right amount of nutrition and this can even disrupt digestion. Then, you may also get problems like nausea and constipation.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;4. Avoiding adding artificial sweeteners&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Artificial sweeteners may contain zero calories but studies have shown that may promote weight gain and risk of certain health conditions. Not just that, sugar increases your body’s water needs due to the amount of water required to metabolize sugar. So, while sugary drinks may taste refreshing at first, they can actually be dehydrating.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;If you are one of them who tends to add any artificial flavors or sweeteners to the water, stop doing that right away. Try to avoid anything with sugar, high fructose corn syrup, aspartame, or sucralose. Instead of that, you can opt for lemon, mint, or herbs.&lt;/p&gt;</string>

<string name="water_info_best_time_to_drink">&lt;h1&gt;Best Times to Drink Water&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;1. Right When You Wake Up&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Start your day off right with a big glass of water. Because you can’t drink water while you’re sleeping, you wake up dehydrated. Not only will drinking water every morning help satisfy your thirst, but it will make it easier to sustain healthy hydration habits in the long run. Plus, it can help to improve your mood, brain function, and energy levels.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;2. Before and During a Meal&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Drinking a cup of water before a meal can aid with weight loss because it can help you feel fuller and prevent overeating. On the other hand, drinking water with your food aids digestion, especially with high-fiber foods.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;3. Midafternoon to Avoid the Slump&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Lacking energy around 3 pm? Instead of reaching for another cup of coffee, grab a bottle or glass of water. Consuming caffeine six hours before bed can disrupt your sleep, which can affect your mood the next day. Dehydration may be the root cause of this midafternoon slump, so drinking water can help combat fatigue and other unwanted symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;4. Before, During, and After Exercise&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Suppose you are prepping for a rigorous workout or active event. In that case, you should regularly drink water in the days leading up to the performance vs. consuming lots of water immediately before to avoid bloating. For moderate workouts, try to drink a cup of water 30 minutes prior to starting. Since you lose water and electrolytes through sweat, you should sip on water during and after your workout to keep your body hydrated and replenish any lost fluids.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;5. When You Have a Headache or Migraine&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Headaches and migraines are no fun, especially if they occur on a daily basis. A headache can be a common symptom of dehydration, so drinking more water can be the key to some relief. Dehydration is also a common trigger for migraines, so increasing your water intake may help decrease migraine severity, frequency, and duration.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;With these recommendations in mind of the best times to drink water in a day, set yourself up for success in your routine. Implementing these small changes can make a world of difference in the long run!&lt;/p&gt;</string>

<string name="water_info_replace_with_water">&lt;h1&gt;Replacing Beverages with Water for Health&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;1. You Flush Out Toxins From Your Body&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Drinking too much soda/soft drinks can cause kidney damage. Since kidneys help eliminate toxins and waste from the body, their inability to perform the said function due to high sugar consumption can lead to the accumulation of metabolic waste which can cause a lot of serious health problems.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Water, on the other hand, is a natural lubricant that helps the kidneys to function well. By drinking enough water, your kidneys are able to perform at their maximum helping you flush out toxins from the blood and urine through the bladder, thus helping you keep your body and system clean from the inside out.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;2. You Improve Your Muscles Endurance &amp; Flexibility&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;When it comes to building and maintaining bones, Calcium is one of the important minerals that is required. Consuming large amounts of carbonated drinks (drinks that contain dissolved carbon dioxide) can interfere with calcium absorption, resulting in weak bones and muscles. Thus, in order to prevent this, it is essential that you severely cut back on soft drinks and energy drinks that contain carbonation and replace these with water.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;The importance of water in our bodies can’t be overemphasized. Not many may be aware of the fact that Water constituents a large part of our muscle composition. Water helps absorb and retain essential minerals, which, in turn, helps us maintain healthy and strong bones. As such, by keeping yourself well-hydrated, you are able to not only improve your muscle endurance but you are also able to improve your flexibility, which will help you achieve peak performance in all that you do.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;3. Your Ability To Focus &amp; Concentrate Gets Sharper&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Apart from affecting your physical health, sugary fizzy drinks or carbonated drinks can also hurt your mental health. Over-consumption of these beverages can lead to dehydration and can trigger an imbalance in certain brain chemicals, resulting in issues like depression, poor memory, brain fatigue, and lack of mental clarity.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;By switching over to water, you are able to effectively combat the ill effects of these beverages. Also, by ensuring your body is well-hydrated, you are making sure that your brain, which is made up of 80% of water, is able to access the required amount of oxygen that is needed in order for it to function at an optimal level.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Water helps enhance your ability to focus better. It also helps increase concentration and memory power. Additionally, it reduces daytime fatigue and aids in preventing attention deficit disorders in both – children and adults alike.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;4. You Boost Your Metabolic Rate&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Metabolism refers to the rate at which your body is able to convert food into energy.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Drinking large amounts of sweetened, caffeinated, and carbonated drinks leads to dehydration, which increases the risk of metabolic disorders resulting in weight gain, sugar cravings, lethargy, joint and muscle pains, etc.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;By replacing these drinks with water, you are able to hydrate your body, thus speeding up your metabolic rate, and leading to faster burning of calories. Plus, water helps regulate and manage blood sugar levels keeping fatigued, lethargy, and sugar cravings at bay which further promotes good health.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;5. You Get A Glowing and Healthier Skin Complexion&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;One of the major benefits of replacing your favorite soft drinks with plain water is bright and radiant skin. Aerated drinks are known to cause damage to skin cells and collagen bonds resulting in premature aging, dullness, dryness, dark spots, wrinkles, and others.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Thus, to nullify the effects of these harmful drinks and to detoxify your body, it is advisable that you drink sufficient water on a daily basis. This helps to flush out toxins and facilitates faster production of blood and muscle cells, providing you with a glowing and healthier skin complexion in a very short span of time.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;6. You Are Able To Stimulate Your Digestive System&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Carbonated drinks primarily consist of dissolved carbon dioxide that can cause indigestion and flatulence. Similarly, soft drinks or soda are mostly acidic and high consumption of them can lead to pH imbalance leading to a host of serious digestion problems like bloating, stomach ulcers, diarrhea, gas, and stomach pain.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Therefore, to steer clear of these issues and to achieve a healthy and improved digestive system, switching over to drinking water is essential. Adequate intake of water on a day-to-day basis will help prevent stomach disorders and will improve bowel movements. Plus, it will help improve the balance of pH levels in your body and aid in preventing constipation.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h3&gt;7. Water Improves Blood Circulation&lt;/h3&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Artificial sweeteners found in many sugary drinks and soda can cause some of the blood vessels to perform irregularly leading to an array of health problems such as high blood pressure, increase heart rate, reduce blood flow to the brain and the digestive system, and other vital organs.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;As one of the most crucial elements of human life, water can help improve blood circulation in the body, thereby ensuring that your blood vessels are not impeded in any way. Hence, if you want your blood circulatory system to work efficiently then you need to quit sodas and other sugary drinks as soon as possible and replace these with pure drinking water.&lt;/p&gt;</string>

<string name="water_info_drink_on_empty_stomatch">&lt;h1&gt;Drink Water on an Empty Stomach?&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Water possesses certain properties to improve your health. Here are the various benefits of drinking water on an empty stomach:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Cleanses Your Bowels&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Drinking water on an empty stomach helps in cleansing your bowels. It creates an urge to move the bowel and therefore helps to regulate your digestive tract. If you experience difficulty while passing motion or if you feel constipated, drink plenty of water as it helps in clearing the waste from your body.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Flushes Toxins From The Body&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Drinking water helps in flushing out all the toxins from the body. It helps in detoxifying yourself. It eliminates all the toxins from the body and cleanses the system. Elimination of toxins improves the quality of the skin and brings a glow on the face.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Prevents Headaches&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons for headache is the lack of regular water intake. Dehydration leads to headache. Drinking water not only prevents headache but also arrests bad odor and other dental problems.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Increases Hunger&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Drinking water early in the morning, on an empty stomach, clears all the waste from the body and makes you feel hungry.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Increases Energy&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Drinking water on an empty stomach stimulates the red blood cells to populate at a faster rate, which inturn boosts the energy levels of the body.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Speeds Up Your Metabolism&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;A person on a diet should drink plenty of water for an increased metabolism rate. The metabolic rate increases about 25 percent by drinking water on an empty stomach. Faster digestion also results in healthy weight loss.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Helps In Reducing Weight&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Water has no calories and so drinking plenty of water when on diet is essential as it helps in losing weight. It also flushes out all the toxins and reduces acidity. As water increases metabolism, your body also tends to burn calories faster. This is one of the best strategies to reduce weight.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Improves Your Skin&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Dehydration causes a number of problems, of which skin problem is one. Dehydration causes premature wrinkles and makes the skin porous. Drinking water on an empty stomach regulates blood flow and improves the quality of the skin. It also helps in releasing toxins from the body and makes the skin radiant.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Promotes Healthy Hair&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Drinking plenty of water also promotes healthy and shiny hair. Water makes up to 1/4th of the hair and therefore insufficient intake of water can make the hair strand brittle and weak. Regular intake of water improves and enhances the quality of hair.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Prevents Kidney Stones&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Drinking water on an empty stomach prevents the formation of kidney stones. It also prevents bladder infections. Water dilutes the acids and prevents the formation of stones in the kidney.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Strengthens Immune System&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Drinking plenty of water flushes out all the toxins and prevents infections from spreading through the body. This ultimately strengthens the immune system and keeps the body away from various kinds of infections.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Drink a glass of water on an empty stomach every day, to experience these benefits. &lt;/p&gt;</string>

<string name="water_info_benefit_lemon_water">&lt;h1&gt;Benefits of Drinking Lemon Water&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Aids in digestion&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Acid helps break down food. That’s why there’s so much of it in our stomachs. The acid in lemons may be especially helpful in supplementing stomach acid levels, which tend to decline as we age.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Helps you stay hydrated&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Most of us don’t drink enough water. A daily lemon water habit is an easy way to get your day off on the right foot. How do you know if you’re drinking enough? Your urine is almost clear.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Weight-loss friendly&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;We’re creatures of habit. Ponder the impact of replacing your morning OJ or latte with lemon water. Not just once, but perhaps 20 times a month — and multiply that by 10 years. Your waistline will thank you.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Prevents oxidation&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Like all produce, lemons contain phytonutrients, which protect your body against disease. These phytonutrients have powerful antioxidant properties, which prevent cell damage from oxidation, the same mechanism that causes rust.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Supplies a healthy dose of vitamin C&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Juice half a lemon into your water and you’ll add a mere 6 calories to your diet. Plus you’ll get more than a sixth of your daily vitamin C, which is needed to protect us from cell damage and repair injury.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Provides a potassium boost&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Your body can’t function without potassium. It’s necessary for nerve-muscle communication, transporting nutrients and waste and blood pressure regulation. Fruits and vegetables are important sources of potassium.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;h2&gt;Helps prevent kidney stones&lt;/h2&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Lemon water helps prevent painful stones in those deficient in urinary citrate (a form of citric acid). More importantly, increased fluids help prevent dehydration — a common cause of kidney stones.&lt;/p&gt;</string>

<string name="water_info_is_ok_drink_during_meal">&lt;h1&gt;Is it OK to Drink Water During a Meal?&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;There\'s no concern that water thins down or weakens down (dilutes) the digestive juices or interfere with digestion. In fact, drinking water during or after a meal helps how your body breaks down and processes food (digestion).&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Water is vital for good health. Water and other drinks help break down food so that your body can take in (absorb) the nutrients. Water also makes stool softer, which helps prevent constipation. Choose water when possible instead of drinks full of sugar.&lt;/p&gt;</string>

<string name="water_info_benefit_for_health">&lt;h1&gt;Drink Water: The Benefits for Health&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Getting enough water every day is important for your health. Drinking water can prevent dehydration, a condition that can cause unclear thinking, result in mood change, cause your body to overheat, and lead to constipation and kidney stones. Water has no calories, so it can also help with managing body weight and reducing calorie intake when substituted for drinks with calories, such as sweet tea or regular soda.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Water helps your body:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;Keep a normal temperature.&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;Lubricate and cushion joints.&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;Protect your spinal cord and other sensitive tissues.&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;Get rid of wastes through urination, perspiration, and bowel movements.&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Your body needs more water when you are:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;In hot climates.&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;More physically active.&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;Running a fever.&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;Having diarrhea or vomiting.&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;</string>

<string name="water_info_danger_of_overhydration">&lt;h1&gt;Dangers of Overhydration&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;When a person consumes an excessive amount of water and cells in their brain start to swell, the pressure inside their skull increases. This causes the first symptoms of water intoxication, which include:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;headaches&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;nausea&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;vomiting&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Severe cases of water intoxication can produce more serious symptoms, such as:&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;ul&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;drowsiness&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;muscle weakness or cramping&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;increased blood pressure&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;double vision&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;confusion&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;inability to identify sensory information&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;li&gt;difficulty breathing&lt;/li&gt;\n&lt;/ul&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;A buildup of fluid in the brain is called cerebral edema. This can affect the brain stem and cause central nervous system dysfunction.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;In severe cases, water intoxication can cause seizures, brain damage, a coma, and even death.&lt;/p&gt;</string>

<string name="water_info_why_should_give_baby_water">&lt;h1&gt;Why You Shouldn’t Give Babies Water?&lt;/h1&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Giving babies water can throw off the delicate sodium balance in their bodies, which can be very dangerous. When you give a baby water, it can dilute the sodium in their bloodstream. That can cause a condition called hyponatremia, or what some people may call “water intoxication”.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Among other things, your kidneys help remove excess fluid by filtering it into your bladder (allowing you to pee it out). That essentially keeps your system from flooding with water.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Adult kidneys are about the size of a large avocado, so healthy, grownup kidneys can typically keep up with removing any extra fluids we take in.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;Newborn kidneys, on the other hand, are about the size of a grape. So, it’s easier for your baby’s kidneys to get overwhelmed. And it doesn’t take much for your baby’s body to get more water than it can handle. &lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;When a baby’s (or adult’s) body is overloaded with water, it can begin to dilute their blood. That’s when things get dangerous. Because waterlogged blood lowers the sodium content in your body.&lt;/p&gt;\n&lt;p&gt;When your baby’s sodium content goes too low because of taking in too much water, it can lead to serious symptoms, like seizures and even coma and permanent brain damage. &lt;/p&gt;</string>
</resources>