<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<resources>
    <string name="info_bmi_healthy_body_weight"><![CDATA[<h1>Healthy body weight</h1>\n<p>A BMI calculation in the healthy weight range is:</p>\n<ul>\n<li>For White people: the healthy weight range is 18.5 to 24.9.</li>\n<li>For Black, Asian and other minority ethnic groups: the healthy weight range is 18.5 to 23.</li>\n</ul>\n<p>For people of White heritage, a BMI:</p>\n<ul>\n<li>below 18.5 is underweight</li>\n<li>between 18.5 and 24.9 is healthy</li>\n<li>between 25 and 29.9 is overweight</li>\n<li>of 30 or over is obese</li>\n</ul>\n<p>Black, Asian and other minority ethnic groups have a higher risk of developing some long-term conditions such as type 2 diabetes with a lower BMI. People from these groups with a BMI of:</p>\n<ul>\n<li>below 18.5 is underweight</li>\n<li>between 18.5 and 22.9 is healthy</li>\n<li>23 or more are at increased risk (overweight)</li>\n<li>27.5 or more are at high risk (obese)</li>]]></string>
    <string name="info_bmi_obesity"><![CDATA[<h1>Obesity</h1>\n<p>Obesity is a complex disease involving having too much body fat. Obesity isn\'t just a cosmetic concern. It\'s a medical problem that increases the risk of many other diseases and health problems. These can include heart disease, diabetes, high blood pressure, high cholesterol, liver disease, sleep apnea and certain cancers.</p>\n<p>There are many reasons why some people have trouble losing weight. Often, obesity results from inherited, physiological and environmental factors, combined with diet, physical activity and exercise choices.</p>\n<p>The good news is that even modest weight loss can improve or prevent the health problems associated with obesity. A healthier diet, increased physical activity and behavior changes can help you lose weight. Prescription medicines and weight-loss procedures are other options for treating obesity.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="info_bmi_obesity_causes"><![CDATA[<h1>Obesity causes</h1>\n<p>Although there are genetic, behavioral, metabolic and hormonal influences on body weight, obesity occurs when you take in more calories than you burn through typical daily activities and exercise. Your body stores these excess calories as fat.</p>\n<p>Obesity often results from a combination of causes and contributing factors:</p>\n<h2>Family inheritance and influences</h2>\n<p>The genes you inherit from your parents may affect the amount of body fat you store, and where that fat is distributed. Genetics also may play a role in how efficiently your body converts food into energy, how your body regulates your appetite and how your body burns calories during exercise.</p>\n<p>Obesity tends to run in families. That\'s not just because of the genes they share. Family members also tend to share similar eating and activity habits.</p>\n<h2>Lifestyle choices</h2>\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Unhealthy diet.</strong> A diet that\'s high in calories, lacking in fruits and vegetables, full of fast food, and laden with high-calorie beverages and oversized portions contributes to weight gain.</li>\n<li><strong>Liquid calories.</strong> People can drink many calories without feeling full, especially calories from alcohol. Other high-calorie beverages, such as sugared soft drinks, can contribute to weight gain.</li>\n<li><strong>Inactivity.</strong> If you have an inactive lifestyle, you can easily take in more calories every day than you burn through exercise and routine daily activities. Looking at computer, tablet and phone screens is inactivity. The number of hours spent in front of a screen is highly associated with weight gain.</li>\n</ul>\n<h2>Certain diseases and medications</h2>\n<p>In some people, obesity can be traced to a medical cause, such as hypothyroidism, Cushing syndrome, Prader-Willi syndrome and other conditions. Medical problems, such as arthritis, also can lead to decreased activity, which may result in weight gain.</p>\n<p>Some medicines can lead to weight gain if you don\'t compensate through diet or activity. These medicines include steroids, some antidepressants, anti-seizure medicines, diabetes medicines, antipsychotic medicines and certain beta blockers.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="info_bmi_obesity_diagnosis"><![CDATA[<h1>Obesity diagnosis</h1>\n<p>To diagnose obesity, your health care professional may perform a physical exam and recommend some tests.</p>\n<p>These exams and tests often include:</p>\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Taking your health history.</strong> Your health care team may review your weight history, weight-loss efforts, physical activity and exercise habits. You also may talk about your eating patterns and appetite control. Your health care professional may ask about other conditions you\'ve had, medicines you take, your stress levels and other issues about your health. They may also review your family\'s health history to see if you may be more likely to have certain conditions.</li>\n<li><strong>A general physical exam.</strong> This includes measuring your height; checking vital signs, such as heart rate, blood pressure and temperature; listening to your heart and lungs; and examining your abdomen.</li>\n<li><strong>Calculating your BMI.</strong> Your health care professional checks your body mass index, called BMI. A BMI of 30 or higher is considered obesity. Numbers higher than 30 increase health risks even more. Have your BMI checked at least once a year. This can help pinpoint your overall health risks and what treatments may be right for you.</li>\n<li><strong>Measuring your waist size.</strong> The distance around your waist is known as the circumference. Fat stored around the waist, sometimes called visceral fat or abdominal fat, may further increase the risk of heart disease and diabetes. Women with a waist that measures more than 35 inches (89 centimeters) and men with a waist that\'s more than 40 inches (102 centimeters) around may have more health risks than do people with smaller waist measurements. Like the BMI measurement, waist circumference should be checked at least once a year.</li>\n<li><strong>Checking for other health problems.</strong> If you have known health problems, your health care team will evaluate them. Your health care professional also will check for other possible health problems, such as high blood pressure, high cholesterol, underactive thyroid, liver problems and diabetes.</li>\n</ul>\n<p>Gathering this information will help you and your health care team choose the type of treatment that will work best for you.</p>]]></string>
    <string name="info_bmi_lifestyle_for_obesity"><![CDATA[<h1>Lifestyle for Obesity</h1>\n<h2>Dietary changes</h2>\n<p>Reducing calories and practicing healthier eating habits are key to overcoming obesity. Although you may lose weight quickly at first, steady weight loss over the long term is considered the safest way to lose weight. It\'s also the best way to keep weight off permanently.</p>\n<p>There is no best weight-loss diet. Choose one that includes healthy foods that you feel will work for you. Dietary changes to treat obesity include:</p>\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Cutting calories.</strong> The key to weight loss is reducing how many calories you take in. A typical amount is 1,200 to 1,500 calories for women and 1,500 to 1,800 for men.</li>\n<li><strong>Feeling full on less.</strong> Some foods &mdash; such as desserts, candies, fats and processed foods &mdash; contain a lot of calories for a small portion. In contrast, fruits and vegetables provide a larger portion size with fewer calories. By eating larger portions of foods that have fewer calories, you can reduce hunger pangs and take in fewer calories. You also may feel better about your meal, which contributes to how satisfied you feel overall.</li>\n<li><strong>Making healthier choices.</strong> To make your overall diet healthier, eat more plant-based foods. These include fruits, vegetables and whole grains. Also emphasize lean sources of protein &mdash; such as beans, lentils and soy &mdash; and lean meats. If you like fish, try to include fish twice a week. Limit salt and added sugar. Eat small amounts of fats, and make sure they come from heart-healthy sources, such as olive, canola and nut oils.</li>\n<li><strong>Restricting certain foods.</strong> Certain diets limit the amount of a particular food group, such as high-carbohydrate or full-fat foods and sugar-sweetened beverages&nbsp;</li>\n<li><strong>Meal replacements.</strong> These plans suggest replacing one or two meals each day with their products &mdash; such as low-calorie shakes or meal bars &mdash; and eating healthy snacks.&nbsp;</li>\n</ul>\n<h2>Exercise and activity</h2>\n<p>Getting more physical activity or exercise is an essential part of obesity treatment:</p>\n<ul>\n<li><strong>Exercise.</strong> People with obesity need to get at least 150 minutes a week of moderate-intensity physical activity. This can help prevent further weight gain or maintain the loss of a modest amount of weight. You\'ll probably need to gradually increase the amount you exercise as your endurance and fitness improve.</li>\n<li><strong>Keep moving.</strong> Even though regular aerobic exercise is the most efficient way to burn calories and shed excess weight, any extra movement helps burn calories. For example, park farther from store entrances and take the stairs instead of the elevator. A pedometer can track how many steps you take over the course of a day. Many people try to reach 10,000 steps every day. Gradually increase the number of steps you take daily to reach your goal.</li>]]></string>
    <string name="info_bmi_weight_loss_tips"><![CDATA[<h1>Weight loss tips</h1>\n<h2>DO</h2>\n<ul>\n<li>get active for 150 minutes a week &ndash; you can break this up into shorter sessions</li>\n<li>aim to get your 5 A Day &ndash; 80g of fresh, canned or frozen fruit or vegetables count as 1 portion</li>\n<li>aim to lose 1 to 2 lbs, or 0.5 to 1 kg, a week</li>\n<li>read food labels &ndash; products with more green colour coding than amber and red are often a healthier option</li>\n<li>swap sugary drinks for water &ndash; if you do not like the taste, add slices of lemon or lime for flavour</li>\n<li>cut down on food that\'s high in sugar and fat &ndash; start by swapping sugary cereal for whole grain alternatives</li>\n<li>share your weight loss plan with someone you trust &ndash; they can help motivate you when you have a bad day</li>\n</ul>\n<h2>DON&rsquo;T</h2>\n<ul>\n<li>do not lose weight suddenly with diets</li>\n<li>do not stock unhealthy food &ndash; popcorn, fruit and rice cakes can be healthier alternatives</li>\n<li>do not skip meals &ndash; you might end up snacking more because you feel hungry</li>\n<li>do not finish your plate if you\'re full &ndash; you can save leftover food for the next day</li>]]></string>
</resources>